### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nidhikjha (LinkedIn) medium.com/@menidhikjha (Blog)

### Top Skills

**Python** 

Microsoft Excel HTML

Honors-Awards

Smart India Hackathon 2018 innovation Award

Finalists at Siemens MakelT Real Hackathon 2018

# Nidhi Kumari

Google Summer of Code 2020 & 2019 | Frontend developer | New Delhi

### Summary

Software Developer working with frontend technologies for 2+ years. I enjoy working with React and I am familiar with Redux along with good knowledge about the fundamentals of the web. I am a big advocate for Open Source Software. I have contributed to many open-source organisations like The Tor Project, Mozilla and Systers. I currently operate in an agile workflow and am very familiar with how best this works with the development process as well as a general level of knowledge around sprinting, retrospectives and issues/ tickets.

I am currently looking for opportunities as a front end engineer.

## Experience

Digital Impact Alliance (DIAL) at the United Nations Foundation Google Summer of code 2020 May 2020 - Present (4 months)

#### i8LABS

Frontend Web Developer February 2020 - May 2020 (4 months) New Delhi, Delhi

Ushahidi

Intern

May 2019 - October 2019 (6 months)

Remote

Digital Impact Alliance (DIAL) at the United Nations Foundation Google Summer Of Code May 2019 - September 2019 (5 months) Remote

W3Dev Private Limited

#### Intern

March 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

National Service Scheme Core Member January 2017 - April 2019 (2 years 4 months) New Delhi Area, India

NSS BVP Event Mangement Executive 2017 - April 2019 (2 years) New Delhi Area, India

Google Developer Group - Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering (GDG BVP) Publicity Executive August 2017 - April 2018 (9 months) India

# Education

Bharati Vidyapeeth College of Engineering ,New Delhi Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2016 - 2020)